Who, in the name of God, is getting away with murder?
The Name of the Rose is a drama, thriller, mystery
film directed by Jean-Jacques Annaud.
14th-century Franciscan monk William of Baskerville and his young novice arrive at a conference
to find that several monks have been murdered under mysterious circumstances.
To solve the crimes, William must rise up against the Church's authority and fight the shadowy
conspiracy of monastery monks using only his intelligence; which is considerable.
William of Baskerville, played by Sean Connery.
Bernardo Gui, played by F. Murray Abraham.
Adso of Melk, played by Christian Slater.
Remigio da Varagine, played by Helmut Qualtinger.
Severinus, played by Ilya Baskin.
The Abbot, played by Michael Lonsdale.
The Name of the Rose is a 1986 historical mystery film directed by Jean-Jacques
Annaud, based on the 1980 novel of the same title by Umberto Eco.
Sean Connery stars as the Franciscan friar William of Baskerville,
called upon to solve a deadly mystery in a medieval abbey.
Christian Slater portrays his young apprentice, Adso of Melk, and F.
Murray Abraham his Inquisitor rival, Bernardo Gui.
Michael Lonsdale, William Hickey, Feodor Chaliapin Jr., Valentina
Vargas, and Ron Perlman play supporting roles.
This English-language film was an international co-production between West German, French, and
Italian companies and was filmed in Rome and at the former Eberbach Abbey in the Rheingau.
It received mixed to positive reviews from critics and won several awards, including
the BAFTA Award for Best Actor in a Leading Role for Sean Connery.
Another adaptation was made in 2019 as a television miniseries for RAI.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book,
library, christianity, inquisition, monk.
The tone is mind_bending and emotional and intense.